  {
    "Teacher":"Anil",
    "Email":"avanilkumar@gmail.com",
    "Subjects":[
      "Geography",
      "History",
      "Physics",
      "Biology",
      "Maths"
      ],
      "Geography":[
          {
            "Question":"India is ______ largest country in the world",
            "Opt0":"21",
            "Opt1":"7",
            "Opt2":"15",
            "Opt3":"13",
            "Answer":"seventh",
            "Opt":1,
            "Hint":"India is in Top ten"
          },
        {
          "Question":"What is the capital of Tamil Nadu",
          "Opt0":"Chennai",
          "Opt1":"Delhi",
          "Opt2":"Tripura",
          "Opt3":"Bengaluru",
          "Answer":"Chennai is capital city of Tamil Nadu",
          "Opt":0,
          "Hint":"Check for tamil name in options"
        },
        {
          "Question":"Which country is also called as Sub-continent",
          "Opt0":"Sweeden",
          "Opt1":"USA",
          "Opt2":"Uganda",
          "Opt3":"India",
          "Answer":"India is called sub-continent due to varied cultures,terrain etc...",
          "Opt":3,
          "Hint":"The country is in Asia"
        },
        {
          "Question":"Which is the largest ocean",
          "Opt0":"Atlantic",
          "Opt1":"Indian",
          "Opt2":"Pacific",
          "Opt3":"None of the above",
          "Answer":"Pacific ocean",
          "Opt":2,
          "Hint":"There is airlines on this oceans name"
        },
        {
          "Question":"Which is the biggest continent in the world",
          "Opt0":"Asia",
          "Opt1":"South America",
          "Opt2":"Europe",
          "Opt3":"Australia",
          "Answer":"Asia",
          "Opt":0,
          "Hint":"India is located in largest continent"
        }

        ],
        "History":[
          {
            "Question":"Who is the first Prime Minister of India",
            "Opt0":"Vajpeye",
            "Opt1":"Manmohan Singh",
            "Opt2":"Rajendra Prasad",
            "Opt3":"Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Answer":"The first Prime minister of India was Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Opt":3,
            "Hint":"His birthday is also childrens day"
          },
          {
            "Question":"Who is called Iron man of India",
            "Opt0":"Sardar Vallabhai patel",
            "Opt1":"Bhagat Singh",
            "Opt2":"Veera Pandya Kattabommana",
            "Opt3":"None of the above",
            "Answer":"Sardar Vallabhai patel",
            "Opt":0,
            "Hint":"Belongs to Gujarat"
          },
          {
            "Question":"In which year India got independence",
            "Opt0":"1947",
            "Opt1":"2012",
            "Opt2":"1856",
            "Opt3":"1701",
            "Answer":"Sardar Vallabhai patel",
            "Opt":0,
            "Hint":"Previuos century"
          },
          {
            "Question":"Tajmahal was built by ?",
            "Opt0":"Akbar",
            "Opt1":"Babur",
            "Opt2":"Humayun",
            "Opt3":"Shahjahan",
            "Answer":"Shahjahan",
            "Opt":3,
            "Hint":"He should be husband of Mumtaj"
          },
          {
            "Question":"Who is called as father of our nation",
            "Opt0":"Bhagat Singh",
            "Opt1":"Chandrasekhar Azad",
            "Opt2":"M K Gandhi",
            "Opt3":"C V Raman",
            "Answer":"M K Gandhi",
            "Opt":2,
            "Hint":"He believed in Non Violence is the way to get independence"
          }
          ],
        "Physics":[
          {
            "Question":"E = ?",
            "Opt0":"mc",
            "Opt1":"m/c",
            "Opt2":"m^2c",
            "Opt3":"mc^2",
            "Answer":"mc^2",
            "Opt":3,
            "Hint":"Huge energy from mass"
          },
          {
            "Question":"Newtons 3rd law of motion is:",
            "Opt0":"Mass contnues its motion",
            "Opt1":"For every action there is equal and opposite reaction",
            "Opt2":"Mass tries to stay still",
            "Opt3":"None of the above",
            "Answer":"For every action there is equal and opposite reaction",
            "Opt":1,
            "Hint":"You hit me, I hit you...;-)"
          },
          {
            "Question":"Newtons 3rd law of motion is:",
            "Opt0":"Mass continues its motion",
            "Opt1":"For every action there is equal and opposite reaction",
            "Opt2":"Mass tries to stay still",
            "Opt3":"None of the above",
            "Answer":"For every action there is equal and opposite reaction",
            "Opt":1,
            "Hint":"You hit me, I hit you...;-)"
          },
          {
            "Question":"An orbital relates to ________",
            "Opt0":"energy level",
            "Opt1":"mass",
            "Opt2":"sub energy level",
            "Opt3":"None of the above",
            "Answer":"sub energy level",
            "Opt":2,
            "Hint":"Relates to accurate electron position"
          },
          {
            "Question":"Heaviest sub atomic particle is?",
            "Opt0":"Neutron",
            "Opt1":"Electron",
            "Opt2":"Positron",
            "Opt3":"Proton",
            "Answer":"Neutron",
            "Opt":0,
            "Hint":"It has no charge"
          }
          ],
          "Biology":[
          {
            "Question":"_____ gives green colour to leafs",
            "Opt0":"pesticides",
            "Opt1":"Haemoglobin",
            "Opt2":"Bile",
            "Opt3":"Chlorophyll",
            "Answer":"Chlorophyll",
            "Opt":3,
            "Hint":"Check the one that is present in plants"
          },
            {
              "Question":"Orthopedic is related to ___________  ",
              "Opt0":"teeth",
              "Opt1":"bones",
              "Opt2":"stomach",
              "Opt3":"ear",
              "Answer":"Bones",
              "Opt":1,
              "Hint":"hard parts of body"
            },
            {
              "Question":"Human beings belong to ",
              "Opt0":"mammals",
              "Opt1":"birds",
              "Opt2":"reptiles",
              "Opt3":"microbes",
              "Answer":"mamals",
              "Opt":0,
              "Hint":"In mamal parent take care of children"
            },
            {
              "Question":"Fish breathes through _____",
              "Opt0":"Nostrils",
              "Opt1":"gills",
              "Opt2":"lungs",
              "Opt3":"bones",
              "Answer":"gills",
              "Opt":1,
              "Hint":"check for the parts assosciated with fish"
            },
            {
              "Question":"In the evolution of life. First the life was ______ in nature",
              "Opt0":"reptiles",
              "Opt1":"mammals",
              "Opt2":"aquatic",
              "Opt3":"terrestrial",
              "Answer":"Aquatic",
              "Opt":2,
              "Hint":"Initially earth was hot"
            }
          ],
          "Maths":[
          {
            "Question":"(a+b)^2 = ?",
            "Opt0":"a^2 + b^2",
            "Opt1":"2a + 2b",
            "Opt2":"a^2+b^2+2ab",
            "Opt3":"Cant be derived",
            "Answer":"a^2+b^2+2ab",
            "Opt":2,
            "Hint":"try multiplying a+b with itself."
          },
            {
              "Question":"Sum of 2 sides of a triangle is _______ than the other side",
              "Opt0":"greater",
              "Opt1":"lesser",
              "Opt2":"equal",
              "Opt3":"Cant be derived",
              "Answer":"Sum of 2 sides of a triangle is greater than the other side",
              "Opt":2,
              "Hint":"try extend/cut a triangle into right angled triangle and apply pythagorus theorum"
            },
            {
              "Question":"dy/dx indicates",
              "Opt0":"area",
              "Opt1":"perimeter",
              "Opt2":"slope",
              "Opt3":"Cant be derived",
              "Answer":"derivation of an equation indicates its slope",
              "Opt":2,
              "Hint":"what does y2-y1 / x2-x1  indicate?"
            }

          ]

  }